BRANCH INSPECTION
（分行稽核班）
I'm so bored.
好無聊啊
Really?
是嗎？
There's been no branch inspection since yesterday.
我們已經兩天沒去分行稽核了
That's a good thing.
這挺好的啊
If we're bored, it means all the branches nationwide are running smoothly.
我們沒事做的話 就表示全國各分行都沒什麼問題
There's peace.
平安無事啊
I know, but I feel like I'm getting out of shape.
也是啦，但我感覺身體要生鏽了
Can I ask you something?
你們兩位有時間嗎？
Inspection?
有稽核工作嗎？
Well… not really.
不，不是稽核工作
Administrative support?
那是支援工作？
No.
也不是
Well…
那個…
I want you to help the Secretarial Office.
是去祕書室幫忙
-Help them? -I'll do it.
-幫忙？ -沒問題
Really?
真的嗎？
-Thanks. I appreciate it. -Yes.
-那就拜託你們啦 -是
I have a bad feeling about this.
有個不好的預感呢
Thank you for coming.
歡迎妳們
Welcome. Please enjoy.
歡迎，請慢用
You have to be a wife of the bank's president
竟然在這種地方辦藝術展覽
in order to open an art exhibition at a place like this.
真不愧是總裁夫人啊
This is clearly not a job for Branch Inspection.
這怎麼看 都不是分行稽核班的工作吧？
It's better than sitting all day.
總比一整天坐著好吧？
This is all very new since I've never seen the world of the bankers' wives.
而且我也沒見過銀行家太太們的聚會 這可是全新的體驗呢
Congratulations.
恭喜您了
Thank you for coming.
感謝各位今日蒞臨
It's an honor.
這是我們的榮幸
I was moved by the art. They are all wonderful.
您的畫作都非常棒，讓我心生感動呢
I would like to buy the picture over there.
我想買下那邊那幅畫
Me, too.
-我也想買
That seems to be a pretty tough world.
她們的世界看起來也很不容易啊
I agree.
是啊
Oh. Here comes the president.
總裁來了
PRESIDENT OF TOKYO DAIICHI BANK RYUICHI SERIZAWA
（東京第一銀行總裁，芹澤龍一）
I'm glad you came.
老公，你來了
I happened to have some time.
我正好有時間就來了
It seems to be busy.
看起來很盛大呢
Thank you.
多虧有你啊
He seems to be a calm person.
是個穩重的人呢
You talk as if you've never met him.
怎麼突然說這個呢？
I haven't seen him since the welcoming ceremony.
因為我在入職儀式之後就沒見過他了
Yeah, ordinary employees like us don't see him that often.
他又不是我們這種小職員 隨隨便便就能見到的
Excuse me, can I have a glass of wine?
不好意思，能給我一杯紅酒嗎？
Sure.
好的
What are you doing, Hanasaki?
妳幹嘛呢，花咲？
I am sorry.
非常抱歉
Here you are.
請用這杯吧
Thank you.
謝謝
Ms. Hanasaki, are you in Branch Inspection?
請問妳就是分行稽核班的 那位花咲小姐嗎？
Yes.
是的
I see. It was you.
原來是妳啊
I am Shindo's wife.
我是真藤的妻子
Executive Director Shindo?
真藤常務嗎？
But, how do you know me?
您怎麼會認識我呢？
SHINDO'S WIFE YOSHIKO SHINDO
（真藤常務的妻子，真藤嘉子）
He doesn't usually talk about his work at home.
我丈夫不常在家提及公事
But he told me once that
但有一次他跟我說
he was scolded by a high-spirited female employee.
自己被一位氣勢十足的女職員 教訓了一頓
That person was you, Ms. Hanasaki.
而那位就是妳呢，花咲小姐
Oh, I wouldn't say that I scolded…
我沒有教訓他啦…
It's not a compliment.
這不是誇獎啦
Mrs. Shindo.
真藤太太
Congratulations.
夫人，今天恭喜您了
Thank you for coming.
謝謝妳的到來
Even their wives have a good relationship.
他們的太太們之間的關係很好呢
It seems like it.
看起來是不錯
President Serizawa likes Executive Director Shindo.
芹澤總裁還是挺中意真藤常務的
Please come visit us with your husband. Right, dear?
下回一定要和妳丈夫一起來 對吧，老公？
Yes. Please come.
是啊，一定要來
Thank you very much.
謝謝您
Look! Mr. Soma.
你看…相馬
How scary!
-好可怕
At first glance, it's a world of shining glamor with lots of smiling faces,
乍看之下是閃閃發光 笑臉迎人的名流圈
but it's actually filled with lots of drama.
實際上是一齣宮鬥劇
Executive Director Shindo is a candidate for the next president,
真藤常務是下任總裁的候選人
so his wife seemed to be the object of envy.
他的太太自然就成了眾人嫉恨的對象
It must be tough for the wives who are affected by their husband's careers.
太太們的生活也被丈夫的職場所影響 真是不容易啊
People say that President Serizawa
有人說是芹澤總裁
recommended Mr. Shindo to become the executive director.
把真藤先生提拔為常務的
So it probably makes everyone jealous.
可能就是這點令人嫉妒吧？
The president's wife is at the top of all the bankers' wives.
感覺總裁夫人 是所有銀行家太太的頂點呢
What? What about a banker's wife?
什麼？銀行家太太？
-Here. -Thank you.
-給你 -謝謝
You never miss that kind of thing.
你的耳朵只聽得到這個啊？
We had a chance to see their world today.
我們今天有機會窺探到了那個世界
How was it?
怎麼樣？
Do you think you can be a banker's wife?
妳覺得妳做得成銀行家太太嗎？
Me, too!
“我也想買…”
I don't think I can do that.
我不行啦…
What is that?
什麼意思啊？
By the way, I found an article in the magazine.
對了，我在週刊雜誌上看到一篇文章
About what?
什麼文章？
About the president of your bank.
是關於你們銀行總裁的
-Right. -It's him.
-真的 -確實是他
He's the president, so I thought he'd be arrogant.
本來以為總裁都應該很囂張
But he is smiling with a bear.
沒想到是這樣笑著跟玩偶合照的人
He seems to be a friendly person.
看起來很平易近人呢
I have a good idea, Mai.
對了，小舞
Why don't you become the president's wife?
不如，妳努力當上總裁夫人吧
I told you that I never dreamed of such a thing.
都跟你說過了，我沒有這樣的夢想
You should dream big.
夢想還是遠大一點比較好啊
I agree.
不錯啊
The president's wife is at the top of all the bankers' wives.
總裁夫人是所有銀行家太太的頂點呢
That's a great idea!
真是個好主意
Good morning.
早安
It's shocking. That was a big company.
那麼大規模的公司呢，真沒想到啊
There were rumors.
之前已經有傳聞了
Can't believe Kuranaka went bankrupt.
沒想到藏中建設真的破產了
Bankrupt?
破產？
Did our bank have any business with Kuranaka Kensetsu?
藏中建設跟我們銀行有交易往來嗎？
Yes.
有啊
Will they have unrecoverable debts?
那會不會有無法回收的債務啊？
I'm sure we won't come out of this unscathed.
應該也沒辦法全身而退吧
We're in trouble.
大事不好了…
What's wrong, Mr. Shibasaki?
怎麼了，芝崎次長？
We know that Kuranaka Kensetsu went bankrupt.
藏中建設破產的事我們已經知道了
No, it's not that.
不，不是這件事
He is asking you to come.
他找你們兩位了
Who is?
誰？
Mr. Doujima.
堂島專務
Mr. Doujima?
-堂島專務？
He apparently has a secret mission for the two of you.
他好像有項祕密任務要交給你們
A secret mission?
-祕密任務？
What do you think the secret mission is?
會是什麼祕密任務呢？
I have no idea.
不知道
Senior Executive Director must trust us a lot to send us on a mission.
堂島專務一定是很信任我們 才會交給我們辦吧？
Hanasaki.
花咲
Don't work too hard.
別幹勁十足啊
Bad things happen when you work too hard.
每次妳幹勁十足都沒什麼好事
-Okay? -That's not nice.
-知道了嗎？ -好過分
I want you to do me a favor.
我有一件事想拜託你們
You know that Kuranaka Kensetsu went bankrupt, right?
你們知道藏中建設破產的事吧？
Yes.
是的
We've provided them with 50 billion yen in loans.
我們銀行給予他們的融資金額 是500億
It seems like five billion yen will be unrecoverable.
其中有50億無法回收
Five billion yen…
50億？
The Finance Department is working on that right now.
融資課正在處理這件事
But there is an even bigger problem.
但還出現了一個更嚴重的問題
May I ask what that is?
請問是什麼問題？
President Kuranaka's chaotic management has been revealed.
藏中建設的社長被查出經營混亂
It seems like he has billions in a slush fund.
擁有數十億的行賄資金
The Director of Finance received an email
今早融資課課長收到了一封
from a whistleblower who claims to be an employee
自稱是藏中建設員工的人
of Kuranaka Kensetsu.
發來的告密郵件
May I see it?
請讓我們看看
One hundred million yen from the slush fund
“行賄資金中有一億日元
was given to Tokyo Daiichi Bank as a bribe.
作為賄賂給了東京第一銀行”
Bribery…
賄賂？
So I want you to contact this person and confirm the facts.
我希望你們聯絡這個人 確認一下事實
Why have you assigned us with such an important task?
這麼重要的工作 為什麼要交給我們呢？
If what is written in the email is true,
如果這封郵件的內容屬實
it must be someone of considerable power within our bank.
那他們賄賂的 一定是我們銀行內有權有勢的人
If that person found out about this, he would try to cover up the truth.
而這個人一旦知道了 就會想盡辦法掩蓋真相
But no one cares about what you are doing.
但你們的一舉一動不會引人注目
I see.
原來如此
Will you work on this?
能做到嗎？
Yes, I will.
是，我明白了
Yes.
是
This could become a serious scandal that will shake our bank to its roots.
這件事處理不好的話 可能會演變成動搖銀行根基的大醜聞
Please take care of this.
一切就拜託你們了
-Yes! -You are so loud.
-是！ -妳太大聲了啦
Do you think he will really come?
那個人會來嗎？
He replied and said that he would. Let's wait.
他回覆說會來，我們就等等吧
You're right…
也是
Why are you carrying this?
妳怎麼拿著這個啦？
I thought I'd carry this so that he can recognize us.
我想說拿著這個好讓對方認出來啊
Is that him?
是他嗎？
No.
不是
Why couldn't you bring
還有別的東西可以拿吧？
something like an envelope.
像是信封之類的啊
Who cares?
這個也不錯啊
Are you from Tokyo Daiichi Bank?
你們是東京第一銀行的職員嗎？
Yes.
是的
I am Nishizaki.
我是西崎
I was the administrative manager of Kuranaka Kensetsu.
藏中建設的總務部長
Our company's bankruptcy has caused a lot of trouble for our customers.
這次公司破產 給客戶帶來了非常大的麻煩
I feel a sense of responsibility as an employee.
身為一名員工，我深感歉疚
You wrote in your email that
你在郵件中寫道
our bank received a bribe of 100 million yen.
我們銀行接受了一億日元的賄賂 是真的嗎？
Yes.
是的
It is true.
是真的
Five years ago, our company failed in a real-estate investment
五年前，我們公司投資房地產失敗
and faced serious financial crisis.
陷入嚴重的財務困境
We applied for an unreasonable additional loan from Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
當時我們向東京第一銀行 申請了一筆不合理的追加融資
Did our bank approve the loan and receive money in return?
我們銀行收了酬勞，批准了融資嗎？
Yes.
是的
If this information becomes public,
如果這件事被揭發
it will cause a huge scandal for Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
東京第一銀行就會惹上大麻煩
So I thought I should let you know as soon as possible.
所以我想還是儘早通知你們比較好
I see.
原來如此
Do you know the name of the employee who received the 100 million yen?
請問…你知道接受了 一億日元賄賂的那個人是誰嗎？
He was the Director of Finance at the time of the loan approval.
他是追加融資獲得批准時的 融資課課長
This is a copy of the secret account
這是社長一直藏起來的
the president had been hiding.
祕密帳戶的複印件
Takeshi Shindo…
真藤毅？
It's Executive Director Shindo.
是真藤常務
He was the Director of Finance at headquarters five years ago.
他確實是五年前的融資課課長
I can't believe it's him.
沒想到是真藤常務
But Mr. Soma,
相馬
this can't be enough evidence to prove that he received a bribe, right?
只憑這個，不能作為真藤常務 收賄的證據吧？
No. This is not enough.
是的，這個不能證明什麼
But the money was transferred to the account at Hakusui Bank.
但是，那筆賄款 被匯入了白水銀行的帳戶
So we can't investigate any further.
我們沒辦法再調查下去
I got it.
對了
Do you have a copy of the transfer request form for this transaction?
你有沒有 這筆交易的匯款申請書副本？
That will give us proof.
那個就證據確鑿了
It might be stored in the president's secret storage.
說不定能在社長的祕密倉庫裡找到
His secret storage?
祕密倉庫？
I found storage that the president is using for personal purposes.
我發現社長有個倉庫是作個人用途的
So I made a spare key and inspected it.
就做了一把備用鑰匙私自調查
That's where I found this list.
這些資料也是在那裡找到的
I see.
原來如此
Will you take us there?
你可以帶我們去嗎？
But the president may have gotten rid of them already.
可是，社長說不定已經銷毀了
Please take us there.
拜託你了
This way.
這邊請
Please wait here.
等一下
-Let me help you. -Thank you.
-我幫你吧 -好
Did you find it?
找到了嗎？
This is clear evidence, isn't it?
這可是鐵證啊
Yes.
是的
Someone is coming. Please hurry up.
有人來了，快走
I think the president sent his people here.
應該是社長的人
That was close.
好危險啊
There's no doubt that Executive Director Shindo received money.
真藤常務真的是收了錢 才批准融資的啊？
That seems to be the case.
就是這麼一回事
Why did he do such a thing?
他為什麼要這麼做呢？
He's got rank and honor,
他有地位、有名譽
and is expected to be the president someday.
而且，還是下任總裁的候選人
Isn't it weird that he was swayed with some money?
卻為了這點錢就動搖了 這不是很奇怪嗎？
But he received 100 million yen. That's a fact.
但事實就是他收下了那一億日元啊
I know, but…
我知道
Hanasaki.
花咲
We will leave it to the management from here on.
這件事從現在開始就交給上頭的人了
Our assignment is done.
我們的工作已經完成
Tomorrow, we will report this to Senior Executive Director Doujima.
明天我們會向堂島專務報告
And that's it.
然後就結束了
Good morning.
早安
She isn't usually late…
她很少會遲到的啊
That idiot.
那個笨蛋
Yes.
請進
Excuse me.
打擾了
This is not a place that an ordinary banker can freely visit.
這裡不是妳這種小職員 可以隨意進來的地方吧？
I would like to ask you something as an ordinary banker.
可是，我這個小職員 有一件事情想要問您
What is it?
什麼事？
It's about the loan to Kuranaka Kensetsu.
是有關藏中建設公司融資的事
You approved an additional loan for Kuranaka Kensetsu
五年前，你還是融資課課長的時候
five years ago when you were in Finance.
給對方批准了一筆追加融資，對吧？
I have been in charge of many loans.
我處理過無數的融資業務
I don't remember everything.
不可能全都記得
I'm sure you remember this one.
不，這個你肯定記得
This is a copy of the transfer request form
這是2010年6月10日
issued on June 10th, 2010 when Kuranaka Kensetsu
藏中建設向白水銀行京橋分行客戶
transferred 100 million yen to Takeshi Shindo's account at Hakusui Bank.
真藤毅的帳戶匯入一億日元的 匯款申請書副本
This is your personal account, isn't it Mr. Shindo?
這是你的私人帳戶吧，真藤常務？
Where was that?
妳在哪裡找到的？
I found it inside President Kuranaka's secret storage.
在藏中社長的祕密倉庫裡找到的
Did you receive the money?
你收了他的錢，對嗎？
What am I supposed to deny,
妳都拿出這個了
after you showed me such a thing?
我還能否認什麼呢？
Why?
為什麼？
Why did you do this?
為什麼要做這種事？
Whenever you covered up scandals within our bank,
你每次掩蓋銀行內部的醜聞時
you always said that you're doing it for the bank.
都說是為了銀行才這麼做的
I couldn't understand your ways at all.
我沒辦法理解你的做法
But I understood that you always had
但我知道你一直有個堅定的信念
a strong conviction for doing what's best for the bank.
那就是把銀行的利益放在最優先
But receiving a bribe from a company,
可是，這種從企業受賄的行為
doesn't benefit the bank.
不是為了銀行
It's for your personal benefit.
而是為了你個人的利益
It is not like you--
這一點都不像你的作風…
Hanasaki, that's enough. Shut up.
花咲，夠了，閉嘴！
No, I won't!
我不要！
I still can't believe that you did something illegal like this.
我不管怎樣都不相信 你會做出如此不正當的行為
Please explain to me why you did this.
請說明你的理由
-Excuse me. -Mr. Soma.
-打擾了 -相馬
Executive Director Shindo, I will apologize on her behalf.
真藤常務，我代她向您道歉
Let's go, Hanasaki.
走吧，花咲
What are you doing? Come on.
幹嘛呢？快點
What are you doing without me?
妳幹嘛瞞著我呢？
But…
可是…
-Soma? -Kodama.
-相馬 -兒玉
What happened?
怎麼回事啊？
So that's what it was.
是這麼一回事嗎？
I can't believe that it was Executive Director Shindo.
真藤常務他怎麼會…
You did a great job.
辛苦你們了
Not at all.
沒什麼
Um…
請問…
What will happen to Executive Director Shindo?
真藤常務會怎麼樣？
I can't decide that by myself.
這個不由得我決定
But he must take responsibility for this.
但他必須為此承擔責任
PRESIDENT'S OFFICE
（總裁辦公室）
I see.
這樣啊
This is going to be a problem.
真是傷腦筋呢
Yes.
是的
President, what should we do?
總裁，我們該怎麼做？
Arrange an emergency meeting with the Board of Directors.
立刻召開董事會會議
Huh?
什麼？
These things must be dealt with quickly and fairly.
這種事必須迅速、公正地解決
Right away.
我知道了
I had great hopes for Mr. Shindo.
我本來還對真藤寄予厚望呢
I am disappointed.
真遺憾啊
KURANAKA KENSETSU
（藏中建設）
Tokyo Public Prosecutors Office has started
東京地方檢察廳
an investigation with Kuranaka Kensetsu.
對藏中建設公司展開了調查
It is suspected that there are slush funds worth billions of yen.
該公司被懷疑藏有數十億的行賄資金
Their fraudulent management is about to be revealed.
其惡劣的經營狀況也漸漸浮出檯面
The investigation has finally started.
調查終於開始了
Will they know that our bank received a part of the slush fund?
他們會不會知道我們銀行也受賄了？
It's possible.
應該會吧
In that case, it is going to be a big scandal for Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
這件事一旦被揭發 對東京第一銀行來說就是大醜聞了
Thank you for working hard for our bank
你一直以來為銀行盡心盡力
until now.
真是感激不盡
But now that it's come to this, we have no other choice.
但事已至此，我們別無選擇了
I'm sure you know
我相信你應該知道
what to do.
自己該怎麼做吧？
Yes, I do.
我知道了
Kodama.
兒玉
What is it?
你在這裡幹嘛？
I have something.
我有東西要給你看
-What? -May I?
-什麼？ -可以進去嗎？
Yes.
好
Hakusui Bank's account activity statement?
白水銀行的帳戶活動明細表？
It's Executive Director Shindo's account.
這是真藤常務的帳戶
How did you get this?
你是怎麼拿到的？
I went to Hakusui Bank and met
我去了白水銀行
the person in charge of Kuranaka.
見了負責藏中建設的人
Kuranaka Kensetsu's bankruptcy has caused serious problems
藏中建設的破產也對白水銀行
for Hakusui Bank as well.
帶來很大的麻煩
Their loss is huge like us.
損失的金額跟我們差不多
I asked them to exchange information and they agreed.
我向他們提出共享資訊的建議 他們也同意了
And they gave you this?
然後就給了你這個？
I also offered information that is hidden from the public.
我是用內部情報交換回來的
You did a great job.
你還挺厲害的嘛
Look here.
你們看這裡
Kuranaka transferred 100 million yen to his account on June 10th.
藏中建設在6月10日 將一億日元匯入他的帳戶
He withdrew all the money in cash on the same day.
就在同一天，他把錢取出來了
It's the entire amount.
而且是全額
-Don't you think it's strange? -Yes.
-不覺得很奇怪嗎？ -是的
Why did he withdraw this huge amount of money in cash?
為什麼要取出那麼大筆現金呢？
What did he do with the 100 million yen?
他拿這一億日元做什麼了？
I think he withdrew the money
我覺得他把錢取出來
from his account to give it to someone else.
應該是要急著交給其他人吧？
What?
-什麼？
I heard from someone in Finance
我聽融資課的人說
that Mr. Shindo was strongly opposed to approving Kuranaka's additional loan.
真藤常務一直都強烈反對 通過藏中建設的追加融資
But he approved it at the last minute.
卻在最後關頭批准了
They said someone must have pressured him.
他們還說一定是有人強迫他的
I'm confused.
我不是很明白呢
Listen.
也就是說
Approving the additional loan
批准了原本反對的
that he was originally opposed to,
藏中建設的追加融資
and receiving the bribe were all not done by his own will.
以及收受賄賂的事 都不是真藤常務自願的
Someone ordered him to do so.
是有人指使他那麼做的
Do you mean that someone put pressure on him
所以是有人強迫他
to receive 100 million yen and approve the loan?
收下一億日元後再批准融資？
Executive Director Shindo was used by someone.
真藤常務是被利用的
Is Executive Director Shindo taking the blame for someone?
那真藤常務是要袒護那個人嗎？
Most likely.
應該是
Mr. Kodama. Do you know where Mr. Shindo is now?
兒玉，真藤常務現在在哪裡？
What?
什麼？
Please wait, Mr. Shindo.
等等，真藤常務
What is it now?
有什麼事啊？
Who are you trying to cover for?
你到底想袒護誰？
Cover?
袒護？
What are you saying?
妳在說什麼呢？
You didn't receive the 100 million yen, right?
你並沒有收下那一億日元，對吧？
Mr. Shindo,
真藤常務
you withdrew the entire 100 million yen
你在藏中建設匯入一億日元的同一天
soon after it was transferred from Kuranaka Kensetsu.
馬上就把錢取出來了
Didn't you give it to someone else?
應該是交給某人了吧？
If so, who was it?
那個人是誰呢？
Why won't you tell us?
為什麼不告訴我們？
Is it for the bank?
是為了銀行嗎？
Hanasaki.
花咲
You told me before that you will change the bank.
妳以前跟我說過妳想要改變銀行
But I'm sure you're starting to understand that such a thing
不過，我想妳也該明白了吧？
is impossible.
這是不可能的
The bank will never change.
銀行是不會改變的
You can never change it.
也沒辦法被改變
There are rules and unspoken agreements in the bank
銀行這個地方有內部人員
that people within the bank can understand. That's--
才理解的規矩和潛規則，這就是…
That's how a bank works?
這就是銀行嗎？
-Right. -That's not right.
-沒錯 -不是這樣的
It's wrong that you can't change anything even when things aren't right.
明明知道是不對的，卻不去改變 這是錯誤的
I can't ruin this bank.
我不能毀掉這家銀行！
Are you saying that this bank will be ruined if the truth comes out?
你的意思是 這件事的真相會毀了這家銀行？
Answer me, Executive Director Shindo.
是這樣嗎，真藤常務？
If so…
要是這樣的話…
if that will ruin this bank, then this bank should be ruined.
要是這件事會毀了銀行的話 那就毀掉吧
Don't say such a thing.
別開玩笑了
Excuse me.
我先走了
You've been going back and forth, like a tiger in a zoo.
從剛才開始就這樣走來走去的 妳以為妳是動物園裡的老虎嗎？
Mr. Soma.
相馬
Isn't there anything we can do?
我們什麼都做不了嗎？
I understand that, but…
我也不知道啊
I know that Executive Director Shindo is covering for someone.
真藤常務絕對是在袒護著某人
But he himself is keeping silent.
但他本人都不願開口
There is nothing we can do.
我們還能怎麼辦？
Branch Inspection.
是，這裡是分行稽核班
This is Shindo.
我是真藤太太
Yes?
什麼？
I'm sorry to bother you.
抱歉打擾妳工作了
It's okay. Is there anything wrong?
沒關係，請問有什麼事嗎？
Yes…
嗯
Um…
那個…
Shindo came home earlier.
我丈夫剛剛回家了
He looked strange, so I asked him what happened.
他看起來很奇怪，我就問他怎麼了
He said that he will probably have to quit the bank.
他說他可能會辭掉銀行的工作
Quit? Why?
辭職？為什麼？
I am not doing anything wrong as a banker.
我沒做過銀行職員不該做的錯事
I want you to know that.
我只希望妳能明白這一點
Yes…
是
I think he is trying to protect the bank.
我覺得他是想要守護銀行
But Ms. Hanasaki, I don't get it.
可是，我不明白啊，花咲小姐
I don't understand why he is trying to protect the bank.
他為什麼要守護銀行到那種地步呢？
What's the point of sacrificing his life
甚至為了銀行犧牲自己的人生
for the bank?
這有什麼意義呢？
For me, the honor of my husband, Takeshi Shindo, is far more important
對我而言，比起銀行的名譽
than the honor of the bank.
我更在乎我丈夫真藤毅的名譽
Ms. Hanasaki, would you please save Shindo for me?
花咲小姐 妳能不能幫我救救我丈夫？
Is this Executive Director Shindo's schedule book?
這是真藤常務的筆記本嗎？
Yes.
是的
I secretly brought a few years' worth.
我瞞著他偷偷拿來了這幾年的筆記本
I think you can find something in them.
這裡面應該有什麼線索
He always takes notes.
因為他是個經常寫筆記的人
But why are you asking me to do this?
妳為什麼會找上我呢？
He told me before that
他之前跟我說過
you are a young, naïve idealist who knows nothing about banks.
妳是個想法幼稚、只會說漂亮話 對銀行的事一無所知的人
However…
不過…
A reckless banker like her might be the one
如果有人能改變 拘泥於陳腐作風的銀行
who can change an old-fashioned bank that is bound by its habits.
說不定就是像她那樣莽撞 不考慮後果的銀行職員吧
That's why I think I can trust you, Ms. Hanasaki.
所以，我才認為妳是值得信任的人
I will take these.
這些先由我保管吧
Thank you.
拜託了
June 10th…
6月10日
HAKUSUI BANK 100M TO RS
（白水銀行，一億，R.S）
What is this?
這是什麼？
What does this mean?
什麼意思呢？
100M should be the amount of money. He gave it to a person named RS.
一億指的是那筆錢 所以是把錢給了R.S
RS?
R.S？
Oh, no…
不會吧？
Could it be…
應該是吧
Ryuichi Serizawa.
芹澤龍一
President Serizawa.
是芹澤總裁
Huh?
什麼？
I can't believe this.
真不敢相信
But it explains why Mr. Shindo is keeping this a secret.
可是，這麼一來，就能解釋 為什麼真藤常務隻字不提了
Yeah.
是啊
Is Executive Director Shindo trying to cover for President Serizawa?
所以真藤常務想袒護的人 就是芹澤總裁嗎？
He feels indebted to President Serizawa.
真藤常務應該是想報恩吧
And if the president's fraudulent act is brought to light,
而且，萬一總裁的不正當行為被揭發
it would be an unprecedented scandal.
那可是前所未有的大醜聞啊
It could ruin Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
甚至可能毀了東京第一銀行
Mr. Shindo is trying to prevent that by sacrificing himself.
真藤常務是想犧牲自己，守護銀行吧
But on paper, Mr. Shindo is the one that received the money.
但是，從理論上說 真藤常務就是那個收賄的人
It doesn't say anything about the president.
這上面都沒提過總裁
The schedule book can't be evidence?
這個筆記本可以成為證據嗎？
No, that's not enough.
還不夠呢
Kodama.
兒玉
What are you doing here?
你怎麼會在這裡？
Mr. Araki. What's the matter?
荒木室長，有什麼事嗎？
I want to ask you something.
我有件事想問問你們
You investigated
你們兩位
Kuranaka's slush fund, right?
調查了藏中建設的行賄資金，對嗎？
Yes.
是的
Report it at a special board meeting the day after tomorrow.
你們需要在後天的董事會會議上 報告一下
But it is…
可是這件事…
Is there a problem?
有什麼問題嗎？
No.
沒有
But we haven't found out the truth yet.
但是，我們還沒查清楚真相
The truth?
真相？
Executive Director Shindo received a bribe.
真藤常務收受賄賂
That's everything.
這就是真相
The entire bank may suffer the consequence because of him.
我們整間銀行 可能會因為他惹上大麻煩
This is unacceptable.
這簡直不可理喻
Listen. Reveal all of Mr. Shindo's bad deeds.
聽好了，揭發真藤常務的所有惡行
Soma, this is a chance for you to distinguish yourself.
相馬，這可是你立功的機會啊
You don't want to stay here forever taking care of small assignments, right?
你也不想一輩子待在這種地方 處理那些無關緊要的小事吧？
-Let's go, Kodama. -Okay.
-走吧，兒玉 -是
Is this how it should be?
這樣真的可以嗎？
Executive Director Shindo will take responsibility,
就這樣讓真藤常務承擔責任
and President Serizawa
而罪魁禍首芹澤總裁
will be left unharmed.
卻繼續逍遙法外
This is supposed to be wrong.
這樣明明就是不對的
For the first time in my life, I seriously want to
我還是第一次認真地考慮…
quit this bank.
想要離開這間銀行
Hanasaki.
花咲
You can't quit.
妳不能離職
If you leave the bank,
如果妳就這樣離開
you won't be able to raise your voice against the wrong deeds anymore.
就再也不能為錯誤的行為發聲了
We can't change things even when we speak out.
再大聲也改變不了什麼
That's our bank.
這就是現在的銀行
But Hanasaki,
但是，花咲
when everyone stops speaking up,
如果再沒有人站出來說話…
this bank will really see its end.
那這家銀行才是真正地完蛋了
Let's go find the 100 million yen.
我們去找那一億日元的下落吧
The president received money from Kuranaka Kensetsu.
芹澤總裁確實收了藏中建設的賄賂
We will find the evidence.
那我們就把證據找出來
That's the only way.
這是唯一的辦法
But if you do such a thing you'll…
但是，這麼做的話，你就…
Do you think I want to be promoted at this bank right now?
妳覺得我想在這樣的銀行 出人頭地嗎？
If I have to keep my mouth shut in order to survive here,
如果必須視而不見 才能在這裡生存下去
they can kiss my ass. Am I right?
那就見鬼去吧，對吧？
Yes.
對
See you tomorrow.
-辛苦了
-Come in. -Thanks. Let's go.
-進來吧 -不好意思啊
This way.
這邊
Let's check the president's schedule on June 10th, 2010.
我們要查查看芹澤總裁 在2010年6月10日的行程
Okay.
好的
He must have received the cash from Mr. Shindo somewhere
他一定是在銀行外面的某個地方 從真藤常務手中
outside the bank.
接過了那一億日元
SCHEDULE JUNE 10TH 2010
（2010年6月10日行程表）
SEARCH
（查詢）
Huh?
什麼？
It seems like he stayed at the bank all day.
他好像一整天都在銀行裡啊
He didn't go out.
沒出去過呢
I see.
這樣啊
He might not have gone on his own.
他可能不是自己去的
He wouldn't want to attract attention.
本人去的話，太引人注目了
Maybe he sent his secretary.
可能是讓祕書去的
How about checking the records of the company car?
不如查查看公務用車的行車記錄吧
This is the record for the president's car in June 2010.
這是芹澤總裁公務用車 2010年6月的行車記錄
Thank you.
謝謝
DRIVING RECORD
（行車記錄）
He came to headquarters from his house in Yoyogi-Uehara.
他從代代木上原的家來到了本部
This car went out after that.
之後車子就出去了
At 11:30 a.m., this car went from headquarters to Kyobashi.
在11點30分從總部前往京橋
Araki?
荒木？
It seems like Mr. Araki used this car.
是荒木室長用的車
He was the president's secretary five years ago.
他在五年前是芹澤總裁的祕書
This is the address of Hakusui Bank's Kyobashi Branch.
這個地址 不就是白水銀行的京橋分行嗎？
Really?
真的嗎？
So Mr. Shindo withdrew the 100 million yen
也就是說，真藤常務
that was transferred from Kuranaka Kensetsu,
領出藏中建設匯入的一億日元
and Mr. Araki received it in place of the president?
而荒木室長 代替芹澤總裁收下了那筆錢
What's important is where the money went after that.
重點是，那筆錢之後去哪了？
After that, the car went to…
之後，車子開到了…
The address is Ginza.
地址是銀座
It's the address of Fujiyama Kikinzoku.
藤山貴金屬
Why did he go there?
他去那裡幹嘛？
Did he buy gold worth 100 million yen?
他把那一億日元換成黃金了嗎？
Gold bars worth 100 million yen…
把一億日元換成金條啊
It is about 5,000 yen per gram,
金價每克五千日元
so gold bars worth 100 million yen would weigh 20 kg.
一億日元的話，就是20公斤
Considering the weight of gold, it must be about this size.
按黃金的比重來看，大約是這麼多
It is smaller than I thought.
比想像中還小呢
This is not good.
這就糟了
If he stored that in a deposit, we'll never be able to find it.
如果是收在保險箱的話 我們就不可能找到了
Where did he go next?
之後去哪了？
-Minami-Senju. -Minami-Senju?
-南千住 -南千住？
He went back to headquarters after that.
然後就回總部了
Is there a place to store the gold bars?
那裡有保管金條的地方嗎？
I can't tell what's there from this map.
從地圖上看不出那是什麼地方呢
He visited those two places after receiving the cash,
他收了錢之後，只去了這兩個地方
so there should be something there.
這兩個地方一定有線索
We must go there.
我們去看看吧
Okay.
好
FUJIYAMA KIKINZOKU
（藤山貴金屬）
Hello.
歡迎光臨
There are many things other than gold bars and accessories.
不止有金條和首飾呢
Hello, Hanasaki. How is it going?
喂？花咲，那邊怎麼樣？
The place Mr. Araki visited after Fujiyama Kikinzoku,
荒木室長離開藤山貴金屬後
is a paint factory in Minami-Senju.
來到了南千住的塗料工廠
Paint company?
塗料工廠？
Yes. It doesn't seem like
是啊，看起來不像是
gold bars worth 100 million yen are hidden in here.
有什麼地方能夠藏住一億日元的金條
I see people coloring statues and artworks.
這裡好像是 給雕像或藝術品上色的工廠
Coloring?
上色？
Yes. I wonder why he came here.
是啊，來這裡幹嘛呢？
Hanasaki.
花咲
I think I know where the 100 million yen went.
我想我猜到那一億日元去哪裡了
What?
什麼？
DAY OF THE MEETING WITH THE BOARD OF DIRECTORS
（董事會會議當天）
Let's start the meeting with the Board of Directors.
董事會會議現在開始
As you may know, today's topic is about the money
我想大家都知道今天的議題
from Kuranaka Kensetsu's slush fund that was
是關於傳言中藏中建設給予本行的
given to our bank.
行賄資金
Branch Inspection has investigated this case.
分行稽核班已經調查了這件案子
They will give us the report.
接下來請兩位報告調查結果
I am Soma from Branch Inspection.
我是分行稽核班的相馬
I am Hanasaki.
我是花咲
Let me explain what we have found.
接下來，我們將說明調查的結果
It is said that Kuranaka Kensetsu
消息指出藏中建設
has a slush fund worth billions of yen.
擁有高達數十億的行賄資金
We were told that our bank received some of that money.
而其中一筆錢流入了我們的銀行
So we met the former administrative manager of Kuranaka Kensetsu.
我們見過了藏中建設的總務部長
From there, we found out that
從而發現到
an employee at our bank had received 100 million yen as a bribe five years ago.
我們銀行的某位職員 在五年前接受了一億日元的賄賂
Kuranaka Kensetsu had financial problems at the time,
當時藏中建設陷入了財務困境
so they paid money in order to get approved for an additional loan.
就以行賄的手段獲得追加融資
This is a copy of the transfer request form for that transaction.
這是那筆錢的匯款申請書副本
June 10th, 2010. The total amount is 100 million yen.
時間是2010年6月10日 總金額是一億日元
Transferred to a personal account at Hakusui Bank.
收款方是白水銀行的個人帳戶
The account holder is Takeshi Shindo.
而帳戶持有人是真藤毅
It's Mr. Shindo's account.
這是真藤常務的帳戶
It was Mr. Shindo.
真的是真藤啊
It wasn't a rumor?
不是謠言啊
Executive Director Shindo.
真藤常務
Do you admit that this is true?
你承認剛才說的是事實嗎？
Is that true, Mr. Shindo?
是真的嗎，真藤？
Please wait.
請等一下
What is it?
怎麼回事？
We haven't finished yet.
我們還沒報告完畢
Huh?
什麼？
It is true that 100 million yen was transferred to
那一億日元確實是在五年前
Mr. Shindo's account five years ago.
被匯入了真藤常務的帳戶
However, Executive Director Shindo didn't receive that money.
然而，真藤常務並沒有收下那筆錢
He was just used by someone.
他只是被人利用了
What does that mean?
什麼意思？
After 100 million yen was transferred,
就在一億日元被匯入的當天
it was immediately withdrawn by Mr. Shindo on the same day
真藤常務馬上就在白水銀行京橋分行
at Hakusui Bank Kyobashi Branch, and it was handed over to Mr. Araki.
以現金取出了全額 並交給了荒木室長
Am I right, Mr. Araki?
對吧，荒木室長？
What are you talking about?
妳在胡說什麼呢？
I know nothing about that.
我什麼都不知道
I have never gone to Hakusui Bank.
我也沒去過白水銀行
This is a record of the president's company car.
這是芹澤總裁公務用車的行車記錄
It is recorded that on June 10th, 2010,
上面記錄了 2010年6月10日那天
Mr. Araki used the president's company car
荒木室長乘坐著這輛車
to go to Hakusui Bank's Kyobashi Branch.
前往了白水銀行京橋分行
I don't know.
我不知道
I didn't do that.
我沒做過那種事
We understand that you would do no such a thing on your own.
你確實不敢擅自做出這種事
Everything was done by the order of one person.
這一切…都是有人指使你做的
This person put pressure on Mr. Shindo,
這個人在五年前
who was the Director of Finance five years ago,
對當時擔任融資課課長的 真藤常務施壓
to approve the additional loan for Kuranaka Kensetsu.
要他批准藏中建設的追加融資
In return, he had 100 million yen transferred
作為回報 這個人收了一億日元的賄賂
not to his personal account, but to Mr. Shindo's account,
但並非轉入他的個人帳戶 而是利用了真藤常務的帳戶
and sent his secretary Mr. Araki, to receive the money.
然後，他就指使自己的祕書 荒木室長去收錢
There's only one person at this bank who could have done such a thing.
這間銀行內只有一個人能做到這件事
It was you, President Serizawa.
芹澤總裁，那就是你
How could you say such a thing to the president?
妳怎麼可以對總裁說這種話？
It is an insult.
妳這可是侮辱啊
Do you know what you are saying?
妳知道自己在說什麼嗎？
Ms. Hanasaki.
花咲
Do you have any evidence to prove what you have just said?
你們有證據證明剛才所說的話嗎？
Yes, I do.
是，有的
Why did you bring such a thing?
怎麼拿出這個？
I am sorry.
不好意思
But I borrowed it because we really needed this.
我們需要它，所以借用了一下
As you know, this is our bank's mascot, named Daichi-kun, created to
大家都知道這個是為了紀念 芹澤總裁上任一週年時製作的
commemorate the first anniversary of
銀行吉祥物
Mr. Serizawa's presidency.
大智君
This is to be given to you as a gift when you retire.
預定在將來總裁卸任的時候
-Am I right? -Yes.
-贈予總裁的禮物，對吧？ -是的
So what?
你到底想說什麼？
Please look.
失禮了
Hey! What are you doing?
喂，妳在幹什麼啊？
This is pure gold.
這個是純金打造的
This evidence proves that President Serizawa
這就是證明芹澤總裁
received the 100 million yen.
收受一億日元賄賂的證據
I will explain where the 100 million yen went
五年前 真藤常務取出了一億日元現金
after Mr. Shindo withdrew it in cash and handed it over to Mr. Araki.
把錢交給荒木室長 之後那筆錢去了哪裡呢？
We traced the records of his car.
我們追蹤了這份行車記錄
Mr. Araki went to Fujiyama Kikinzoku in Ginza
荒木室長先去了 位於銀座的藤山貴金屬
and received the golden statue of Daichi-kun that was ordered beforehand.
取走了事先訂製好的純金大智君雕像
He paid for the statue with 100 million yen in cash.
並支付了一億現金的費用
Right after that, he went to a paint factory in Minami-Senju,
然後他就去了位於南千住的塗料工廠
to cover the gold statue with paint.
請他們給這座金雕像上漆
It was to camouflage the fact that this statue is pure gold.
目的是要掩飾 這座雕像是純金打造的事實
This is a copy of the receipt for the gold statue,
這是我們從藤山貴金屬借來的
that we borrowed from Fujiyama Kikinzoku.
訂製金雕像的收據副本
This is the order form received by the paint factory
而這張是委託千住塗料工廠
to paint the statue.
為雕像上漆的訂單
Both were clearly signed by Mr. Araki.
這兩張單據上 都清晰地保留了荒木室長的簽名
No, it was…
不，那是…
Everything was done by President Serizawa
這一切都是芹澤總裁的計畫
because he received 100 million yen from Kuranaka Kensetsu
他收受了藏中建設給的一億日元賄賂
and wanted to keep it at hand without causing any suspicion.
想要神不知鬼不覺地收下這筆錢 才設下這個局
Do you admit it?
我說的沒錯吧？
I don't know anything about that.
你說的我都不知道
I am the president of Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
我是東京第一銀行的總裁
I would never do such a thing.
我不可能做出這種事
Wasn't it Mr. Shindo who received the bribe?
受賄的人不是真藤嗎？
This scandal was caused by Shindo.
鬧出這場醜聞的人是真藤
I have nothing to do with it.
與我無關
I don't get it.
可是，我不明白啊
I don't understand why he is trying so hard to protect the bank.
他為什麼要守護銀行到那種地步呢？
What's the point of sacrificing his life
甚至為了銀行犧牲自己的人生
for the bank?
這有什麼意義呢？
Would you please save Shindo for me?
妳能不能幫我救救我丈夫？
With all due respect…
恕我直言
The person who caused this scandal is you, President Serizawa.
鬧出這場醜聞的人是你才對 芹澤總裁
What?
妳說什麼？
You're just an ordinary employee.
只不過區區一個小職員
-Shut up. -No, I won't!
-閉嘴 -我不要！
The boss takes credit for the achievements
功勞歸上司
but blames his subordinates.
失誤由下屬承擔
That rule is only accepted at this bank.
也只有這家銀行會接受這種規則
Even a child can tell that it is wrong.
即使是三歲小孩都知道是錯的事
But at this bank, bosses naturally force their subordinates
在這家銀行卻像是理所當然的一樣
to take blame for their mistakes, responsibilities,
上司把自己的失誤、責任 甚至是不正當行為
and even wrongdoings.
都交給下屬承擔
However, everyone working at this bank
但是，在這間銀行工作的所有人
is a human being before they are a banker.
在銀行職員的身分之前也是一個人
Everyone has their own precious family and personal lives to look after.
大家都有各自珍惜的家人和人生
That's why they all grit their teeth and continue to work.
所以，他們才會咬緊牙關、拼命工作
When I see those people suffering, I get so frustrated
我看到這些人痛苦的樣子就很不甘心
that I have to speak out.
不吐不快
This bank is wrong.
這家銀行確實做錯了
Mr. Shindo.
真藤常務
Do you…
你不是說過
still insist on protecting this kind of a bank?
即使是這樣的銀行 你也想要守護嗎？
Is it worth sacrificing your faith, life, and family
就算要犧牲 自己的信念、人生，甚至是家庭
to protect this bank?
你也想守護它，不是嗎？
Is there anyone who can teach this rude employee a lesson?
沒有人要教訓一下 這個無禮的女職員嗎？
Ms. Hanasaki.
花咲
You might be right.
妳說的可能是對的
When I was the Director of Finance five years ago,
五年前，身為融資課課長的我
I approved the additional loan for Kuranaka Kensetsu.
批准了藏中建設的追加融資
A few days after that, 100 million yen was transferred
過了幾天，我的個人帳戶
from Kuranaka Kensetsu to my personal account.
就收到了藏中建設匯來的一億日元
I handed…
我把那筆錢
the money over to Mr. Araki…
交給了荒木室長
even though I knew that it was a bribe.
即使我知道那是一筆賄款
Everything…
這一切
was ordered by President Serizawa.
都是芹澤總裁的指示
Shindo!
真藤
I accepted everything because
我默許了這一切，是因為
I always thought it was best for the bank.
我以為這麼做是為了銀行好
If it came out that the president did something illegal,
如果總裁的不正當行為被揭發
this bank would be ruined.
這家銀行可能就完了
That's what I thought.
我是這麼想的
But I was wrong.
但是，我錯了
If we keep doing such things,
如果再這樣下去
this bank will one day rot and decay.
這家銀行總有一天會腐敗、衰落
It needs to be changed before that happens.
在那之前要改變才行
I mean,
不對
we must change it.
是必須有所改變
Change?
改變？
Are you trying to deny the history of our bank? Then try that!
你是想要推翻我們銀行的歷史嗎？ 你試試看啊
It will ruin this bank!
那樣才會毀了銀行
With all due respect…
恕我直言
if that will ruin this bank,
如果改變會毀了銀行
then this rotten bank should be ruined.
那如此腐敗的銀行就應該被毀掉
Here I witness the incident of injustice
我在此指證 芹澤總裁所做的不正當行為
by President Serizawa,
並且
and apologize for having taken part in it.
為自己牽涉其中深感歉意
I am very sorry.
真的十分抱歉
Shindo!
真藤！
Damn you…
你這傢伙
I have been taking special care of you.
虧我一直以來那麼關照你
Who do you think put you in that position?
你以為是誰把你捧上這個位置的？
I call for the president's removal.
我動議罷免現任總裁的職務
Please stand up…
贊成的人
if you give your approval.
請起立
The president has been removed from his post
全體同意罷免總裁職務
by unanimous vote.
沒有異議吧？
We have news that
日本三大銀行之一
the top management of Tokyo Daiichi Bank
東京第一銀行的高層
received 100 million yen of illegal funds
被揭發收取了藏中建設
from Kuranaka Kensetsu.
給予的一億日元賄款
Former President Serizawa is under investigation now
為此，前任總裁芹澤龍一
by the Tokyo District Public Prosecutors Office.
正在東京地方檢察廳接受審訊
Mom.
媽
I really wanted to quit the bank this time.
我本來這次真的想辭掉銀行的工作了
But the bank is not as rotten as I thought.
但是，銀行並沒有我想像中腐敗呢
So I will work harder.
所以，我會繼續努力的
Whoa.
真是的
Don't come in so quietly.
怎麼一點脚步聲都沒有？
You were just absentminded.
是妳心不在焉吧？
No, I wasn't.
沒有啊
I heard from Mr. Soma that you spoke out in front of the president.
我聽相馬說 妳當著總裁的面直話直說了呢
That blabbermouth.
那個大嘴巴
I can't even ask for a discount when I purchase ingredients.
我買材料的時候，連討價還價都不敢
You are just like your mom.
妳一定是遺傳了妳媽的性格吧？
Am I?
是嗎？
That's what I really loved about your mom.
我就是喜歡妳媽這一點
Dad.
爸
-That's a little creepy. -Mai.
-感覺有點噁心 -小舞
I have to go now.
我要出門了
Do you have everything you need?
東西都帶齊了吧？
I am not a kid in elementary school.
我又不是小學生
-Oops. -See?
看吧
Please go to the Takasaki Branch for an inspection.
今天要去高崎分行進行稽核工作
Good luck.
拜託你們了
Yes.
-是
It's time for the speech by our new president.
差不多是新總裁上任的發言時間了
Hello, everyone at Tokyo Daiichi Bank.
東京第一銀行的全體同仁
I am Doujima, and I have been appointed as the new president.
我是這次新上任的總裁堂島
Kodama.
兒玉
Yes!
是
Thank you.
謝謝你的照顧
I can't agree with this.
我無法接受
Why have you been transferred to a subsidiary company?
您被調遣到分公司這件事
Even though I was just being used,
就算我只是被利用的
I kept hiding the injustice.
我依舊一直包庇這個不正當行為
I have to take responsibility for that.
我確實需要為此承擔責任
I will wait for your return.
我會等您回來的
As a result of the reports regarding the recent incident,
受到一連串有關事件報導的影響
many customers have closed their accounts
很多客戶都關閉了帳戶
and we have lost many business partners.
我們也流失了不少企業夥伴…
It must be tough to become the president at a time like this.
在這種時期上任真是不容易啊
Mr. Karashima.
辛島部長
Those two left already for the inspection.
他們兩個已經出去稽核了哦
I didn't notice.
什麼時候走的啊？
Until now, our bank had been relying on our position as a mega bank
我們銀行一直以來 作為肩負日本經濟的大銀行之一
that supported the Japanese economy.
地位可謂相當穩固
But I can make it clear now that
但我今天想澄清一點
Tokyo Daiichi Bank was wrong.
東京第一銀行做錯了
What are you doing?
你們在這裡幹嘛？
We are going to the Takasaki Branch to inspect the loss of passbooks.
我們要去高崎分行調查存摺遺失的事
-I see. -Yes.
-這樣啊 -是的
Um…
那個…
I will continue to work hard and do my best from now on.
我會繼續努力做自已能力所及的事
So that when you come back, you will notice the difference
等您回來的時候，就會察覺到
in this bank, even if it's only a small change.
銀行變得不一樣了 哪怕只是小小的改變
You may not have enough time.
妳可能沒那麼多時間呢
I will be back soon.
我馬上就會回來的
With all due respect…
恕我直言
I will be fine
沒問題的
because I will start working hard right away.
因為，我也會馬上開始努力工作
Excuse me.
告辭了
I will get rid of this bank's internal rules.
為了除掉銀行內部的潛規則
We must change our bank.
我們必須做出改變
-We are late. -Let's go.
-要遲到了 -走吧
If the bank is ruined by doing that,
如果改變會毀了銀行
then such a rotten bank should be ruined.
那如此腐敗的銀行就應該被毀掉
A female employee taught me that.
這是一名女職員教會我的
Who is he talking about?
他說的是誰呢？
Today's lunch is Himokawa udon.
今天的午餐就吃寬烏龍麵吧
No. Let's eat pasta.
義大利麵吧
I want to ask for help from all employees all over Japan.
我希望全國的銀行職員 都能助我一臂之力
Each person's power may be meager,
一個人的力量也許很微薄
but it will become a bigger power when we work together.
但只要大家團結起來 一定會形成一股強大的力量
Today is the day we take our first step.
我們就從今天起邁出第一步
Let's change Tokyo Daiichi Bank together.
一起改變東京第一銀行吧
-Why don't we eat both? -Sure.
-不能兩個都吃嗎？ -可以啊
Okay. Let's work hard!
好，就這麼決定了 那今天也要好好加油
Okay.
好
Hey! Wait for me.
喂，妳等等我啊
THIS DRAMA IS FICTIONAL
（本故事純屬虛構）